Guide to the Margery Sved papers, 1972-1985 RL.11295
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Margery Sved papers
1972-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Sved, Margery
RL.11295
36977
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
Margery (Margie) Sved, PhD is a psychiatrist practicing in the Triangle area of North Carolina. She champions issues related to women and members of the LGBTQ community in medicine.The Margery Sved papers document women's health organizations and events in the Triangle area from the 1970-80's, including a notebook from a conference sponsored by AMWA (American Medical Women's Association) at Duke in 1980 on Leadership for Women in Medicine. There is also a file on an early conference of lesbian physicians.
Scope and Contents
The Margery Sved papers contains materials documenting women's health organizations and events in the Triangle area of North Carolina from 1972-1985, including educational materials, notes from conferences and workshops related to women and minorities in medicine, and publications on women's health.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Margery (Margie) Sved, PhD, is a psychiatrist in Raleigh, North Carolina. She received her medical degree from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill School of Medicine and has been in practice for more than 37 years.
She is an active member of the AMWA (American Medical Women's Association); AAPHR (American Association of Physicians for Humans Rights); American Psychological Association's Committee of Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual Issues and other prominent organizations. She is part of a committed group of lesbian physicians advocating for visibility related to mental health issues for women and minorities, particularly within the LQBTQ community.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Margery Sved papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift 2015.
Women psychiatrists -- North Carolina; Lesbians -- Mental health; Lesbians -- North Carolina; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Accession (2015-0037), 1976-1984
  - Durham Women's Health Cooperative (Box 1)
  - Women's Health Teaching Group- Pelvic Exam (Box 1)
  - Women's Group Articles (Subject: Women and Psychology) (Box 1)
  - Women in Medical Academia Leadership Workshop in Educational Equality, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Women in Medicine, 1978 (Box 1)
  - List of Female UNC Medical Faculty, late 1970's (Box 1)
  - Communicating with the Media, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Sex Role Socialization in Education (Box 1)
  - Tables on the Current Status of Women in Academic Medicine, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Title IX Material (Box 1)
  - Quiz on Women in Medicine, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Leadership for Women in Medicine, October 31-November 2, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Minority Women in Medicine Workbook and Resource Manual, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 2nd National Lesbian Physician's Conference Program and Proceedings, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Women in Medical Academia Newsletter, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - Publications on Women's Health, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Motivation of Me and Others by Dr. Eva Schinder-Reinman, 1976 (Box 1)